(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-09-28T22:25:34.489833",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
せーの
Ready, set...
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that's no good,
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
See, if it's like that,
心は進化するよ
my heart will evolve,
もっと もっと
more and more!
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If it's a relationship that disappears once phrased,
言葉を消せばいいやって
then I thought I should just erase the words.
思ってた
I thought,
恐れてた
I was afraid,
だけどあれ？
but wait, huh?
なんか違うかも...
Maybe something's different...
千里の道も一歩から！
A journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step!
石のように硬いそんな意志で
With a resolve as hard as stone,
塵も積もれば大和撫子？
If dust piles up, does it become a proper lady?
「し」抜きで いや 死ぬ気で！
Leaving out "shi"—no, as if my life depends on it!
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Fluffy, floating softly,
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで舞い上がる
Just you calling my name makes me soar high.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Softly floating, light and gentle,
あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
Just seeing you smile makes me smile too.
神様ありがとう
God, thank you.
運命のいたずらでも
Even if it's a trick of fate,
めぐり合えたことが
that we were able to meet...
しあわせなの
...makes me so happy.
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that's no good,
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
See, if it's like that,
心は進化するよ
my heart will evolve,
もっと もっと
more and more!
そう そんなんじゃ いや
Yeah, I don't want it like that,
ねぇ そんなんじゃ まだ
Hey, it's not enough yet,
私のこと見つめててね
Keep your eyes on me,
ずっと ずっと
forever and ever.
私の中のあなたは ほら
Look, the "you" inside of me,
あなたの中の私の存在は
and my presence inside of "you"...
まだまだ 大きくないことも
I know that it's still not very big,
分かってるけれど
yet even so,
今この同じ 瞬間
Right now, sharing this exact same moment,
共有してる 時間
this shared time together...
塵も積もれば大和撫子
Even dust, piled up, becomes a Yamato Nadeshiko,
略して 塵つも 大和撫子
Shortened to: "Dust-piled Yamato Nadeshiko"!
クラクラリ クラクラル あなたを見上げたら
Dizzy, dizzying, when I look up at you,
それだけで 眩しすぎて
just that alone is far too dazzling.
クラクラル クラクラリ あなたを思っている
Dizzying, dizzy, just thinking about you,
それだけで 溶けてしまう
just that alone makes me melt away.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも
even if it's just a trick of fate,
巡り合えたことが
being able to meet you
幸せなの
makes me so happy.
コイスルキモチは トコトンパティシエ サーキュレーション
In-love feelings, a full-on pastry chef circulation!
コイスルオトメは トコトンパティシエ サーキュレーション
A maiden in love, a full-on pastry chef circulation!
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Fluffy, floating,
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで
when you call my name, just that alone
宙へ浮かぶ
makes me float into the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Floating, fluffy,
あなたが笑っている それだけで
when you're smiling, just that alone
笑顔になる
puts a smile on my face.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも
even if it's just a trick of fate,
巡り合えたことが
being able to meet you
幸せなの
makes me so happy.
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that's just not enough,
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
come on, that's not going to do!
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart will keep evolving, more and more!
そう そんなんじゃ いや
Yeah, I don't want it to end like that,
ねぇ そんなんじゃ まだ
hey, that's still not enough,
私のこと 見ててね ずっとずっと
keep your eyes on me, forever and always!
《 逆光のフリューゲル 》
[Song: Gyakkou no Flügel]
「聞こえますか…？」 激情奏でる ミュージック
"Can you hear it...?" Music playing with passion,
天に 解き放て
unleash it into the heavens!
「聴こえますか…？」 イノチ始まる 脈動
"Can you hear it...?" A pulsation marking life's start,
愛を 突き上げて
thrust love upward!
遥か
Far, far...
彼方 星が 音楽となった… 彼の日
away, the day when stars became music...
風が 髪を さらう 瞬間
The moment the wind sweeps through our hair,
君と僕は コドウを 詩にした
you and I turned our heartbeats into poetry.
そして 夢は ひらくよ
And so, dreams blossom,
見た事ない 世界の果てへ…
toward the edge of a world never seen before...
Yes, just believe
神様も 知らない ヒカリで 歴史を創ろう
Let's create history with a light unknown even to God!
逆光のシャワー 未来 照らす
A shower of backlighting illuminates the future,
一緒に 飛ばないか
won't you fly together with me?
Just feeling
涙で 濡れた羽 重くて 羽撃けない日は
On days when wings wet with tears are too heavy to flap,
Wish
その右手添えよう
Let's lend a hand to that right hand,
僕の チカラも
my strength as well!
二人でなら 翼になれる Singing heart
Together, we can become wings — a singing heart!
いつの日にか 解る時が 来るから
Because a day will come when you will understand,
ずっと… 忘れない
I will never... forget,
その時には 心のあるがままに
when that time comes, follow your heart as it is!
笑顔…忘れない
Smile... I won't forget
きっと君は
Surely, you are
一羽の鳥のように
like a lone bird
遠い過去と
Connecting the distant past
手と手繋ぎ
hand in hand
大空を強く翔けていたんだ
soaring strongly through the vast sky.
そして生きる今を
And looking upon the living present
見た事ない明日へ…
towards an unseen tomorrow...
Yes, just believe
1000年後の今日も
Even today, 1000 years later,
生まれ変わって歌いたい
I want to be reborn and sing.
暖かいよ
It's warm
このぬくもり
this warmth,
絶対離さない
I will never let it go.
Just feeling
運命なんてない
There's no such thing as fate
物語は自分にある
The story lies within yourself
Just 逃げ出したくなったら
Just if you feel like running away,
宇宙を見上げよう
look up at the cosmos.
勇気こそが輝くんだよ
Courage is what shines.
Singing star
遥か彼方
Far beyond
星が音楽となったかの日
on that day when stars became music
たぶん僕は君と出会い
I probably met you
神話の一つのように紡いだ
and spun a tale like a myth.
何も怖くないよ
Nothing is frightening
見た事ない世界の果てへ…
towards the end of an unseen world...
Yes, just believe
神様も知らない
Not even God knows,
光で歴史を創ろう
let's create history with light.
逆光のシャワー
A shower of backlighting
未来照らす
illuminates the future.
一緒に飛ばないか
Won't you fly together with me?
Just feeling
涙で濡れた羽
Wings soaked in tears,
重くて羽ばたけない日は
on days when they are too heavy to flap,
Wish 旋律は溶け合って
Wish, the melodies melt together
シンフォニーへと
into a symphony.
二人になら翼になれる
Together we can become wings.
Singing heart
もっと高く
Higher and higher
太陽よりも高く
higher than the sun
Unhappy 名のある人の子よ
Unhappy child of a distinguished house
Unlucky 行き先無き者
Unlucky wanderer with nowhere to go
Be happy ためらわず目指せ
Be happy, aim forward without hesitation
生きているんだし
Since we're alive anyway
目を逸らした過去も
The past you averted your eyes from
退屈な未来も
and the boring future
カウンセリング やれやれ
Counseling, oh dear
古今東西 ピースピース
Everywhere across all times, peace peace
Unhappy / Unlucky
Be happy / UNDEAD
ねえ なんでどうして
Hey, why and how come
戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
I feel like I'm fighting someone?
触れられない 触れたくもない
Untouchable, don't even want to touch
過去の自分
My past self
もうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
Fighting transparent ghosts long dead
幼気で痛い 記憶の奥
Deep within childish, painful memories
もう居ないのに
Even though they are no longer there
あれ？すれ違い アイロニーね
Huh? Passing by each other, what irony
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is the one being seen through my present self?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, unerasable labels
弱コンプレックス
Weak complex
取り憑かれてるみたい 巻き付いたまま
As if possessed, wound tightly
まだ離れない
Still won't part
執着の自分
Obsessive self
UNDEAD 死んじゃいない
UNDEAD, not dead
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain reaction between you and yourself
生きていることとは 変わり続けることだ
To live means to keep changing
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't content yourself with unhappiness
幸せになろうとしないなんて 愚かだ
Not trying to be happy is foolish
この世はこの世は奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world is a bizarre fantasy
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will a demon or a snake appear next?
出会って遭遇っと始まる物語
A story that begins upon meeting and encountering
さあ 一か八かものか
Now, all or nothing
Past & Future can't change the Past
Past & Future run for the Future
何だかどうせ
Somehow, anyway
未来になんぞ何の希望もない
There's no hope for the future anyway
ような気がして
or so it feels
もう随分生きてる 既視感とテンプレで食傷
Living for so long, fed up with deja vu and cliches
素敵な出来事の気配もない
No sign of any wonderful events either
残念 積んだ経験の因果
Pity, the karma of accumulated experiences
形骸化された神話 退屈な進化
Fossilized myths, boring evolution
要は刺激が欲しいんだ 飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
In short, wanting stimulation, got tired, got used to it
なんて 整っていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス
And so on... guidance being set up, increasing compliance
蓋をされてくみたい
It feels like being covered up
吸い尽くして
Sucking everything dry
あれも これも どれも
That, this, whichever one
同じ味がする
They all taste the same
死んじゃない
Not dead
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain between you and yourself
何時の世も 過去も 未来も 現在にあるんだ
Every age, the past, the future, all exist in the present
生きていることを 愚直に果せよ
Fulfill living with simple honesty
目指せ ハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending
死んじゃない
Not dead
お前に言っているんだ
I'm telling you
幸せを諦めてしまうな
Don't give up on happiness
ひとり通り
Passing through alone
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
Just getting used to suffering and enduring it
死んでるも同然 屍のアンデッド
Is as good as dead, a corpse of an undead
UNHAPPY? UNLUCKY? 弱気者
Unhappy? Unlucky? The faint-hearted,
拙ならざる者も者も
Even those who are imperfect,
松明目指せよ
aim for the torch!
生きているなら
If you are alive,
不幸に浸るも
wallowing in unhappiness,
幸せになるも
or becoming happy,
そう全部全部お前だ
it's all entirely up to you!
古今東西 一切合切 森羅万象 ピースピース
All of time and space, everything in creation, peace peace!
Past & Future
can't change the past
run for the future
一人なる所に いつも霊異こと
Where one is alone, strange phenomena always occur
生き抜けこの 化物ばかりの物語
Survive this story filled with monsters
Stop listen rewind
Come a little closer
Listen to the silence beating hard
Where ever you go
Fast forward in time
Times moving in deeper
All deeper and deeper into you
There is no way out
It must have been the time when I lost my way
Through the chaos of time it was stormy
Spinning out of it all
You left me in life of confusion
Take a time to remember when I met you
See the truth beneath all the lies and hate
Nothing wrong being scared
We're all the same tomorrow
Hear what I'm saying
Rewind our vision
I want to hold you
Please take a moment now
Let me into your heart
Rewind your vision
Don't let it hold you back and today
Just explore
We can fall in love
You know the truth is there
Let me know why
Between us love
Stop my tears rewind
Over lapping blue shadows
Touching in the darkness far away
Wishing it was real
Stay with me tonight
I don't want this sadness
Sadness overflowing in my mind
I wanna hold on
Hear what I'm saying
Rewind your vision
I want your heart beat
I want you wanting me
Let me into your heart
Rewind your vision
I can't remember days are without you
Take my hand
We can fall in love
You know the truth is there
Let me know why
Between us love
with...
lonely night
I want...
until...
Yeah
Nothing more...
Yeah!
Rewind our vision
I want to hold you
Please take a moment now
Let me into your heart
Rewind your vision
Don't let it hold you back and today
Just explore
We can fall in love
You know the truth is there
Let me know why
Between us love
Yeah
Love
いつも通りのある日のこと
On an ordinary day like any other,
君は突然立ち上がり言った
you suddenly stood up and said,
「今夜星を見に行こう」
"Let's go look at the stars tonight."
君の知らない物語
[The Story You Don't Know]
「たまには良いこと言うんだね」
"You actually say good things sometimes,"
なんてみんなして言って笑った
everyone teased and laughed together.
明かりもない道を
Along a path with no lights,
バカみたいにはしゃいで歩いた
we walked, foolishly goofing around,
抱え込んだ孤独や不安に
so as not to be crushed
押し潰されないように
by the loneliness and anxiety held within.
真っ暗な世界から見上げた
Looking up from a pitch-black world,
夜空は星が降るようで
the night sky looked as if stars were falling.
いつからだろう 君のことを
Since when was I...
追いかける私がいた
chasing after you?
どうかお願い
Please, I beg you,
驚かないで聞いてよ
don't be surprised, just listen to me:
私のこの思いを
these feelings of mine.
「あれがデネブ、アルタイル、ベガ」
"That's Deneb, Altair, and Vega."
君は指差す夏の夏の大三角
You point to the Summer Triangle,
覚えて空を見る
and I remember and look up at the sky.
やっと見つけた織姫様
I finally found Orihime,
だけどどこだろう彦星様
but where is Hikoboshi?
これじゃひとりぼっち
At this rate, she's all alone.
楽しげなひとつとなりの君
Next to me, you look so happy,
私は何も言えなくて
while I couldn't say a word.
本当はずっと君のことを
The truth is, all along, about you,
どこかでわかっていた
somewhere deep down, I knew it.
見つかったって
Even if I found it,
届きはしない
it's out of reach.
だめだよ 泣かないで
No, don't cry—
そう言い聞かせた
that's what I kept telling myself.
強がる私は臆病で
Acting tough, I was a coward,
興味がないようなふりをしていた
pretending like I didn't care at all.
だけど
And yet...
胸を刺す痛みは増していく
the piercing pain in my chest keeps growing.
ああそうか 好きになるって
Ah, so this is what it means
こういうことなんだね
to fall in love with someone...
「星が綺麗」と言ってごらん
"Look, the stars are beautiful," you said
心の声がする
I hear the voice of my heart
君の隣がいい
I want to be by your side
真実は残酷だ
The truth is so cruel
言えなかった
I couldn't say it
I couldn't tell you
二度と戻れないあの夏の日
That summer day we can never return to
きらめく星
The twinkling stars
今でも思いだせるよ
Even now, I can still recall them
笑った顔も 怒った顔も
Both your smiling face and your angry face
大好きでした
I loved them so much
おかしいよね
It's funny, isn't it?
わかってたのに
Even though I already knew
君の知らない 私だけの秘密
A secret of mine that you never knew
夜を越えて 遠い思い出の
Crossing through the night into distant memories
君が指をさす
Where you point your finger
無邪気な声で
In an innocent voice
Broken Wings
[Song: Broken Wings]
I know this will not remain forever
However it's beautiful
Your eyes, hands and your warm smile
They're my treasure
It's hard to forget
I wish there was a solution
Don't spend your time in confusion
I'll turn back now and spread
My broken wings, still strong enough to cross the ocean with
My broken wings, how far should I go drifting in the wind
Higher and higher in the light
Still strong enough to cross the ocean with
My broken wings, how far should I go drifting in the wind
Across the sky, just keep on flying
計測のできない痛みと 計測のできない時間の流れが
The immeasurable pain and the immeasurable passage of time
すべてを埋めてしまおうとしても
Even if they try to bury everything...
それでも私には感じられる
Even so, I can still feel it
空から落ちてくるのは
What falls from the sky...
雨ではなくて...
Is not rain, but...
Did I ever chain you down to my heart
Cause I was afraid of you?
No, I couldn't hold any longer
Love is not a toy
Let go of me now
The time we spent is perpetual
Our future is not real
So I'll leap into the air
still strong enough to cross the ocean with my broken wings
How far should I go drifting in the wind
Higher and higher in the light
still strong enough to cross the ocean with my broken wings
How far should I go drifting in the wind
Across the sky, just keep on flying
keep on flying
空から落ちてくるのは
What falls from the sky...
あれは雨ではなくて…
...is not rain...
認めていた 臆病な過去
I had accepted my cowardly past
分からないままに 怖がっていた
Fearing it without even understanding it,
後ろの正面だれが 現実を今に映す
Who is behind me, reflecting reality onto the present?
いつもと空を描いた
I painted the usual sky,
ここはきっと 儚い心 満たして
Here, surely filling this fragile heart.
夢で見でいた 高く跳んだ
Dreaming of it, jumping high,
体はどんな不安纏っても 振り払っていく
No matter what anxiety my body wears, I'll shake it off.
眠る小さな想い 広がりだして
Small, sleeping emotions begin to expand,
いつ 弱い私 君がいれば
Whenever I'm weak, as long as you're here,
暗い世界 強くいれた
I could remain strong in this dark world.
願い夢見る心はそう 永遠で
The heart that wishes and dreams is eternal.
I wanna always be with you, I give you everything I have
探していた 導く光
The guiding light I was searching for,
触れれば すべて
If I touch it, everything...
思い出して かけがえのない 大切な今を
Remembering this irreplaceable, precious present moment.
くれていた世界を知った
I came to know the world you gave me,
それはいつも 温かいのに 痛くて
Even though it was always warm, it hurt.
繋ぐ確かな限界 重なり合って
Connecting our definite limits, overlapping,
見える迷いは 動き始めた
The visible hesitation has begun to move,
君を守りたくて
Wanting to protect you,
背負う偽り 捨てて
I cast off the lies I carry.
深い眠りの中 漂った
Drifting in a deep sleep,
変わらない 約束だった
It was an unchanging promise.
ふたり信じた 絆はそう 鮮明に
The bond we both believed in is so vivid.
声が届くまで 名前を呼んで
Call my name until my voice reaches you,
出会えた奇跡 感じたいもっと
I want to feel the miracle of our meeting even more.
夢で高くとんだ
Dreaming of it, jumping high,
体はどんな不安纏っても 振り払っていく
No matter what anxiety my body wears, I'll shake it off.
眠る小さな想い 広がりだして
Small, sleeping emotions begin to expand,
いつ 弱い私 君がいれば
Whenever I'm weak, as long as you're here,
暗い世界 強くいれた
I could remain strong in this dark world.
願い夢見る心はそう 永遠で
The heart that wishes and dreams is eternal.
I wanna always be with you
I wanna hold you tight right now
I swear I will wipe your tears
I'll give you everything I have
世界で一番お姫様
The number one princess in the world
そういう扱い 心得て
You'd better know how to treat me like one
よね
Right?
ワールドイズマイン CPK! Remix
[World Is Mine (CPK! Remix)]
その1 いつもと違う髪型に気づくこと
Number one: Notice when my hairstyle is different than usual
その2 ちゃんと靴までみること いいね？
Number two: Make sure to look all the way down to my shoes, got it?
その3 わたしの一言には3つの言葉で返事すること
Number three: Reply to my every word with three words of your own
わかったら右手がおるすなのを
If you get it, my right hand is free
なんとかして！
So do something about it!
別にわがままなんて言っていないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything
キミに心から思ってほしいの
I just want you to think from the bottom of your heart...
かわいいって
...that I'm cute!
世界で一番お姫様
The number one princess in the world
気がついて ねぇねぇ
Notice me, hey, hey!
待たせるなんて論外よ
Keeping me waiting is out of the question!
わたしを誰だと思ってるの？
Who do you think I am?
もうなんだか甘いものが食べたい！
Geez, now I feel like eating something sweet!
今すぐによ
Right this instant!
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょ
Flaws? You mean "cute", right?
文句は許しませんの
Complaints will not be tolerated
あのね わたしの話ちゃんと聞いてる？ちょっと…
Hey, are you actually listening to what I'm saying? Hey...
あ それとね 白いお馬さん 決まってるでしょ？迎えに来て
Oh, and a white horse is a given, right? Come pick me up!
わかったらかしずいて 手をとって「お姫様」って
If you get it, bow down, take my hand and call me "Princess"
別にわがままなんて言っていないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything
でもね 少しくらいしかってくれたっていいのよ？
But you know, it's okay if you scold me just a little bit, okay?
世界でわたしだけのお王子様
The prince that belongs only to me in the whole world
気がついて ほらほら
Notice me, look, look!
お手手が空いてます
My hand is empty!
無口でぶっきらぼうな王子様
A taciturn and blunt prince...
もうどうして？気がついてよ 早く
Geez, why? Notice me already, hurry!
絶対にキミは分かってない 分かってないわ…
You definitely don't get it, you don't get it at all...
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ
Shortcake topped with strawberries,
こだわりたまごの熱々プリン
freshly baked pudding made with premium eggs...
みんなみんな我慢します
I'll hold back on all of those!
わがままな子だと思わないで
Don't think I'm just a selfish girl!
わたしだってやればできるもん
I can restrain myself if I try,
後で後悔するわよ
so you'd better not regret this later!
当然です！だってわたしは
It's only natural! After all, I am...
世界で一番お姫様
...the number one princess in the world!
ちゃんと見ててよね どこかに行っちゃうよ
Keep your eyes on me, or I'll wander off somewhere else!
ふいに抱きしめられた 急にそんな えっ？
Suddenly I was hugged... so unexpectedly, wait, what?
「ひかれる危ないよ」そう言ってそっぽ向くキミ
"Watch out, you'll get hit," you say as you turn away...
こっちのが危険だわ！
This is way more dangerous!
はい、ということで！
Alright, moving on!
皆さん！獅白ぼたん生誕祭2026
Everyone! Welcome to Shishiro Botan Birthday Celebration 2026:
「STRAY & STAY」にお越しくださりありがとうございます！
"STRAY & STAY"! Thank you so much for coming!
ということで、ラライヨン獅白ぼたんです！
With that said, I'm La-Lion, Shishiro Botan!
配信のハッシュタグ、改めて右上、右上…
For the stream hashtag, once again, top right, top right...
どっちだ？もうどっちか！
Which way is it? Whichever one!
よろしくお願いします！こっちです！
Please use it! It's over here!
獅白ぼたん生誕祭2026、たくさん呟いてください！わたしもチェックしますんで、よろしくお願いします！
Please tweet a lot with #獅白ぼたん生誕祭2026! I'll be checking them too, so thank you!
ということで
So then,
早速なんですけど
without further ado,
次のパートの...ま、次...の次かな？ちょっと色々あるんですけど
for the next part... well, next... or after next? There's a lot going on,
ま、次のパートのゲストをお呼びして
I'd like to invite the guests for the next part
一緒にちょっとMCをやっていきたいと思います！
and host an MC segment with them!
ということで、来いよ！いつものメンバーたちよ！
So come on out, the usual members!
イェーイ！来たぜ、いつもの！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Here they are, the usual squad! Thank you so much!
いつものメンバーたちがいということで、じゃあちょっと改めて自己紹介してもらおうかな。
Since the usual squad is here, let me have everyone introduce themselves again.
じゃあもう、はい！ねねちゃんから！
Alright, starting with Nene-chan!
はい！ねぽらぼの「ね」、桃鈴ねねです！
Yes! The "Ne" of NePoLaBo, Momosuzu Nene here!
よろしくお願いします！ - おたっしゃでー！
Please treat me well! - Stay healthy~!
はい、次！
Okay, next!
はい次！ねぽらぼの「ぽ」、尾丸ポルカでーす！よろしくお願いします！
Next up! The "Po" of NePoLaBo, Omaru Polka here! Please treat me well!
イェーイ！よろしくお願いします！
Yay! Welcome!
はい、次「ら」！
Okay, next is "La"!
はい！ねぽらぼの「ら」、ホロライブ5期生、顔が肝臓、雪花ラミィです！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! The "La" of NePoLaBo, Hololive 5th Gen, "My Face is My Liver", Yukihana Lamy! Please treat me well!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ということで、お馴染みのメンツ揃いました。
So, the familiar crew is all assembled.
ししろん生誕祭始まっちゃいましたけど、これ、ど...どうですか？
Shishiron's birthday festival has started, how... how are you all feeling about it?
なじみの顔見ると安心するね！ - 良かった良かった！
Seeing familiar faces really puts me at ease! - Glad to hear that!
いやーもう来年もよろしくお願いします！ - えー！？お正月！？
Man, I hope we can work together next year too! - Eh!? Is it New Year's already!?
お正月みたいになっちゃってる - おめでたーい！よいお年を！
It sounds like New Year's! - Congrats! Happy New Year!
ステージめっちゃかっこいい！ - ステージね！かっこいい！
The stage looks super cool! - Right? The stage is awesome!
今回もちょっとネオンピカピカしてますけれど。 - ネオン！ピカピカ！
It's all glowing with neon lights again this time. - Bright neon!
好きだよね！ - 好きだね！やっぱり好きなの結構...
You really love this style, don't you? - I do! I guess I really...
めっちゃ食べる方だからさ、こういうのもめっちゃ使っちゃうよね！ - あーね！
Since I'm the type who consumes a lot of this vibe, I end up using it a lot! - Ah, makes sense!
要素がいっぱいだね！そうなの、近未来的な。
There are so many elements! Right, it's futuristic.
そうなんすよー。
That's right~
ちなみにコンセプトとかあるんですか？
By the way, is there a specific concept for this?
今回結構アニメの曲とかもたくさん歌わせてもらってたんで、
This time I sang a lot of anime songs,
プラスなんか私の好きなそのEDMというかサイバー感が好きなん(で)、
plus I love EDM and futuristic cyber vibes,
ちょっと合体した感じかな？ドパってるドパってる感じ！
so I kind of merged them together! Giving off a high-energy vibe!
うん、ちょっとドパってる感じ！ - ドパってる！？
Yeah, a bit hyped up! - Hyped up!?
ドパってるかー？ - はい！ということでね！
Is it hyped up? - Alright! So with that said,
ここまでをまあ色々振り返ってみようかなとも思ったんですけど、
I was thinking of looking back on everything so far,
どうしようかなー？
what should I do?
なんか私今日1曲目にさ、恋愛サーキュレーション歌ったんですよ！
Like, for my first song today, I sang "Ren'ai Circulation"!
おー！可愛い！可愛かったよ！
Oh! Cute! You were so cute!
可愛かったか？ちょっと久しぶりに、なんか可愛いの見せちゃったなと思って。
Was I cute? It felt like it's been a while since I showed a cute side of me.
ぶりっ子！ぶりっ子入ってた！てれてれ！ - ぶりっこ入ってた？可愛いだろ！
You were playing cute! Blushing! - Was I playing cute? Pretty cute, right!
4歳が出てたよ！ - 出てた？
Your 4-year-old self came out! - Did it?
今回で何歳になった？ - 今回でも4歳から次のフリューゲル...
How old did you turn this time? - Well, starting at 4 years old, by the time I sang "Flügel"...
そらちゃんと歌った時にもう20歳ぐらいになった！ - えー！早い！
...with Sora-chan, I was already around 20 years old! - Eh! That's fast!
飛んだ！かっこよく飛んだから！ - 飛んだから！
You skipped right ahead! A cool leap! - Right, I leaped!
色々ちょっとMCがてら紹介したいことがあって、
There are a few things I'd like to introduce during this MC segment,
ちょっとお手伝いしていただけたら嬉しいなと思ってます！
and I'd love it if you could help me out!
はい！何でしょう？ - じゃちょっと告知、はい、告知させていただきたいと思います！
Sure! What is it? - Let's move on to the announcements!
まずは獅白ぼたん生誕記念2026のグッズの販売告知となります！
First, an announcement for the sales of Shishiro Botan Birthday Celebration 2026 merch!
おー！ - こちら、じゃん！
Ooh! - Here it is, ta-da!
イラストはママ、トマリ先生に書いていただけました！ありがとうございます！
The illustration was drawn by my mama, Tomari-sensei! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
イラストのテーマはね、ちょっとゴシック系の獅白ぼたんに仕上げていただけました！
The theme of the illustration is a gothic-style Shishiro Botan!
似合ってる！可愛い！ - いいでしょ？じゃ詳細ちょっと見ていきましょう！こちら！
It suits you! So cute! - Looks good, right? Let's check out the details! Here!
はい、ステッカー！
First, the sticker!
これはキービジュアルのイラストを使用した大きめサイズのステッカーです！
This is a large-sized sticker featuring the main visual artwork!
貼ってはがせるタイプになっているんで、何回でも使えるかなと思ってます。
It's a removable type, so you can reapply it multiple times.
キラキラホログラム仕様です！ - おー！可愛い！
It has a sparkly hologram finish! - Ooh! Cute!
続いてはこちら！ドゥン！
Next up is this! Dun!
SSRBのエコバッグです！ - エコバッグいいー！
The SSRB Eco Bag! - An eco bag is so great!
ちょっとしたお買い物にね、気軽に持ち歩けるエコバッグになってます。
It's an eco bag you can easily carry around for quick shopping trips.
SSRB型のポーチも付属してるので、その中に収納していただければね、
It comes with an SSRB-shaped pouch, so if you store it inside,
持ち運びも簡単になるかなと思ってます！ - 可愛い！
it'll be super easy to carry! - Cute!
続いてはこちら！ドゥン！
Next is this! Dun!
コンテナBOX！リバイバル...デザインは変わってます！
Container Box! A revival item... with an updated design!
SSRBデザインのコンテナボックスになってて、折りたためる仕様になってます。
It's an SSRB-themed container box that is foldable!
これめちゃめちゃ人気だったもんね！ - そう！
This one was super popular before! - Right!
やっぱね、みんなグッズ増えてきてると思うんで、収納していただけたら嬉しいなと思ってます！
I bet everyone's merch collection is growing, so I'd love it if you use this for storage!
続いてはこちら！
Next is this!
SSRBティッシュカバーです！ - ティッシュカバー！可愛い！
SSRB Tissue Box Cover! - A tissue cover! Cute!
どでかい質感のね、SSRBモチーフのティッシュカバーになってるんで、
It's a soft, plush tissue cover designed after SSRB,
いつでも手元に置いてね、嬉し泣きや涙拭いたりしてくれよな！
so keep it close to wipe away your tears of joy or sadness!
そして、フルセット購入特典あります！こちら！
And we have full set purchase bonuses! Here!
直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージ入りのポストカードです！
A postcard with my handwritten signature and a foil-stamped message!
トマリママのイラストが最高なので、ぜひフルセットで購入していただけたら嬉しいなと思ってます！
Tomari-mama's artwork is top-tier, so I'd be super happy if you get the full set!
フルセットだねー！ - 待ってます！
Full set is the way to go~ - We'll be waiting!
そして2つ目のお知らせ、こちら！ほい！
And the second announcement is this! Here!
なんと！獅白ぼたんの新曲「STRAY & STAY」！
My brand-new original song, "STRAY & STAY"!
この後24時、9月20日日曜日の0時からデジタル配信されます！
It will be released digitally starting tonight at 24:00, Sunday, Sept 20th at midnight!
イェーイ！
Yay!
今回は「シミリクル」を作ってくれたShiNoRiRi先生が作ってくれたんですよ、また！
This song was composed again by ShiNoRiRi-sensei, who wrote "Similcle"!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
これはなんかね、多分「スルメ曲」だと思う！
I think this song is what you'd call a song that gets better the more you listen to it!
なんかずっと味がする！
It feels like it keeps giving flavor!
ずっとリピートしてもらえると
If people keep repeating it,
なんかどんどん...
it feels like, more and more...
噛めば噛むほど...
the more you chew,
ドパドパしてくるんじゃないかなと...
dopamine keeps flowing...
ドパドパしてくるんじゃないかなと思って
I thought dopamine might keep flowing!
ドパドパじゃないだろ
It's not "dopamine"!
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Alright, please look forward to it!
はい！
Yes!
この配信が終わった後、MV公開されますので
The music video will be released after this stream ends,
ぜひお楽しみにということで、新曲ちなみにこの後披露しますので絶対に聴いてください！
so please look forward to it! By the way, I'll perform the new song later, so make sure to listen!
聴いてねー！
Please listen!
そして3つ目のお知らせ！まだまだあります！
And now for the third announcement! There's still more!
こちら！ドン！
Here it is! Bam!
ということで、私、獅白ぼたんのファーストアルバムが発売決定しましたー！
So, the release of my, Shishiro Botan's, first album has been confirmed!
おめでとー！素晴らしい！
Congratulations! Amazing!
記念すべき、はい、ファーストアルバムということで、たっぷり10曲入ってます！
To celebrate my first album, it includes a generous 10 tracks!
イェーイ！
Yay!
今年リリースした『シミュラクル』から『トキハナテ』の4曲に加えて、
In addition to the four tracks released this year, from "Simulacra" to "Tokihanate",
この生誕ライブに合わせて、椎乃味醂さんに書き下ろしてもらった新曲『Stray & Stay』はもちろん収録されています！
the new song "Stray & Stay," written for this birthday live stream by Shiino Mirin, is of course included!
さらにさらに！まだちょっとネタバレになっちゃうから伏せたいんですけど、
Furthermore! It's still a spoiler so I want to keep it a secret, but...
素敵なクリエイターの皆様に書き下ろしていただいた新曲が5曲入ってます！
five new songs written by wonderful creators are also included!
豪華ー！
How lavish!
何体？よくわかんない！足し算できない！
How many? I don't know! I can't do math!
獅白ぼたんのね、音楽を存分に感じてもらえる1枚になってるかなと思いますので
It's an album where you can fully experience Shishiro Botan's music,
ぜひよろしくお願いします！はい！
so please check it out! Yes!
そして、アルバムゲットしてくれた皆さんに感謝の気持ちを込めて、全員に直筆サイン入りのグッズも用意していますので！
And to show my gratitude to everyone who gets the album, we've prepared autographed goods for everyone!
え、全員！？
Wait, everyone?!
その他、たくさんここでしか手に入らない、こだわりグッズ詰め込んでますので、ぜひ詳細は公式ページをチェックしていただけたら嬉しいです！
Plus, plenty of special items you can only get here are packed inside, so please check the official page for details!
はい、よろしくお願いします！
Yes, please check it out!
本当におめでとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Congratulations! Thank you so much!
このアルバムはですね、ホロライブ公式オンラインショップでこの後予約開始となります！
Pre-orders for this album will start right after this on the official hololive online shop!
頑張って作ったファーストアルバムなので、たくさんの人に手にとってもらえると嬉しいです！
I worked really hard on this first album, so I hope many people pick it up!
よろしくお願いします！
Please check it out!
そしてですね、まだあるんですよ、実は！
And well, there's actually still more!
まだあるの？！もうお腹いっぱいよ！
There's more?! We're already full!
ラストのこのお知らせ、結構重大発表なので、こちらご覧ください！ドン！
This last announcement is a pretty big one, so please look at this! Bam!
緊急告知！！
[Emergency Announcement!!]
獅白ぼたん 特殊なオフイベ
Shishiro Botan special off-site event
開催決定！
is confirmed!
ということで、2027年2月末から3月中旬あけといてね！
So, keep late February to mid-March 2027 open!
長くね？！※1日じゃないよ
That's long?! *Not just one day
ということで、皆さんぜひ楽しみにしといてもらえたら嬉しいなと思ってます。
So, I hope everyone looks forward to it.
まだ詳細はね、ごめん、ちょっと言えないんだけど...気になる！気になる！
Sorry, I can't reveal the details yet, but... Curiosity rises!
ねぽらぼの皆さんも、ちょっとね、来てほしいなと思いつつ...
I hope Nepolabo can come as well...
え、いいの？！
Wait, really?! Can we?!
なんか、まだ内緒だけどね。何でー？！ネタバレになっちゃうから。
It's still a secret though. Why?! Because it'll be a spoiler.
まあ、何て言ったらいいのかな...遊びに来てほしいかなって感じ。
Well, how should I put it... I want you to come hang out.
へー！すごい、楽しみ！
Woah! Sounds so exciting!
ちょっと楽しみにしていてください。全力でふざけちゃうよ！ふざけてほしい！
Please look forward to it. We're gonna mess around with full force! Please do!
ま、2月末から3月中旬予定になっておりますので
Well, it's scheduled from late February to mid-March,
ぜひ、あの情報解禁色々ね、またしていくので、はい、チェックよろしくお願いします！
so please keep an eye out as we reveal more information!
ということで、以上、獅白ぼたん誕生日記念2026のグッズ情報、アルバムリリース情報、新曲情報、そして重大発表お知らせでした！皆さんよろしくお願いします！
So, that was all the info on Shishiro Botan Birthday 2026 goods, album release, new song, and major announcement! Thank you everyone!
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
じゃあみんな、はい、スタンバイ、スタンバイ！
Alright everyone, stand by, stand by!
ここからですね、いよいよライブも終盤戦ということで、
From here on out, the live stream is entering its final stage,
ねぽらぼのみんなも、この後一緒に歌わせていただきますので！
and Nepolabo will be singing together with me afterwards!
はい！リスナーの皆さん、ぜひ楽しみに待っててくだーさい！
Yes! Everyone watching, please look forward to it!
あと限定アンコールライブもね、今日ありますので、ぜひそちらも来ていただけたら嬉しいです！
Also, there's a member-exclusive encore live today, so please come join that as well!
アンコールあるで！楽しみや！
There's an encore! So excited!
じゃあ私、ちょっと次の曲の衣装に着替えるんで、じゃあみんなちょっと繋いどいてもらっていい？
Alright, I'm going to change into my outfit for the next song, so can you guys fill in for a bit?
繋いどこ！ししろーの特殊なオフイベ予想しよう！
Let's fill the time! Let me guess Shishiro's special off-site event!
え、でもそれ当たっちゃったらどうすんの？
Wait, but what if we get it right?
当たらない程度に大きく行こう！
Let's go big enough so we don't hit it right on the nose!
じゃあ、獅白ランド開催！
Then, opening Shishiro Land!
いいね！動物園！
Nice! A zoo!
それとかどうかな？特殊なオフイベって言っても...
How about that? A special off-site event...
これ以上言うとバレル可能性がある...
If you say any more, you might spoil it...
やめろやめろ！あぶないあぶない！
Stop, stop! That was close!
当てられそうだったからちょっと...着替えてきました！
Felt like you were about to guess it right, so I came back after changing!
ということで、じゃあ、ねぽらぼのみんなもね、ちょっと準備して...
Alright then, Nepolabo everyone, go get ready...
また後でね！バイバイー！
See you later! Bye-bye!
ということで、ねぽらぼともね、この後歌うんですが、まずはちょっと次の曲、私の新曲を聴いていただきたいなと思いますので、
So, I'll be singing with Nepolabo next, but first I'd like you to listen to my new song,
ぜひ聴いてください！
so please give it a listen!
それでは、『Stray & Stay』。
And now, "Stray & Stay".
Losing the faint light
形のない、層に沈む感覚の様
Like a shapeless feeling sinking into layers...
不安定な位相が 走る思考
An unstable phase, racing thoughts,
引き千切られた記憶を跨ぎ
Straddling torn-apart memories...
昨日と同じ軌道を描く日常に 散らばった 重なり合った 思考の線
Scattered and overlapping lines of thought in a daily routine tracing yesterday's path.
Stay, Stay, Stay in my place
Stray, Without a trace
ぐちゃぐちゃになった言葉が
Before these jumbled words...
消えてしまう前に
...fade away completely...
掴みたいと
Wanting to reach out and grasp it...
願った ただ繰り返した
I wished, and simply repeated it...
ただ繰り返した
Over and over again...
また繰り返して
Repeating it once more...
まだ 離さないでいて
Please don't let go of me just yet.
Waking from a shallow sleep
形のない 夜に滲む 知覚の様
Like perception seeping into the shapeless night...
未完成な鼓動 またも煌々と輝く
An incomplete heartbeat, brightly shining once more...
仮構を追う 同じ過去を辿る焦燥
Chasing fiction, the impatience of tracing the same past...
拭いきれぬ透明な模造
An indelible, transparent imitation.
Sway, Sway, Sway out of place
Stray, Fading away
ぐちゃぐちゃになった言葉が
Before these jumbled words...
色褪せる前に
...lose their color...
書き留めたいと
Wanting to write it all down...
思ってた ただ繰り返した
I thought, and simply repeated it...
ただ繰り返した
Over and over again...
また繰り返して
Repeating it once more...
まだ 忘れないでいて
Please don't forget me just yet.
共に限界まで Burning!
Burning together to the limit!
X-BRAVERS Are you ready? Fight!
Lala... Rurila...
何度地べたに網いずり 土を噛んだって
No matter how many times we crawl on the ground and bite the dust...
防人合い 背を任す 戦場に咲く友がいる
Protecting each other and trusting our backs, we have friends blooming on the battlefield!
ガチンコで本気 危険在時も なぜか立ち向かえる
Truly serious in a real fight, even in danger, somehow we can face it head-on!
フォルツァンドの限界値まで フォルテーロ 銀河に溺れよう
To the critical limit of Sforzando, Fortero! Let's drown in the galaxy!
Burn Burn Burn Burn Burn ブルっだって突き出せる
Burn! Burn! Burn! Burn! Burn! Even if we shiver, we can thrust forward!
Burn Burn Burn Burn Burn 濁しても振り絞れ
Burn! Burn! Burn! Burn! Burn! Even if clouded, wring out every last drop!
人が作る想いの 答えを信じよう
Let me believe in the answer of feelings created by people!
ハートを狂わせて 愛を穿て
Drive your heart wild and pierce through love!
100度負けても 101度目に
Even if we lose a hundred times, on the 101st...
勝てる（誇れ） この力とは
...we will win! (Be proud!) What is this power?
みんなが（今日も） 紡いだ（この） 歌と響きだ
It's the song and resonance spun by everyone today!
交わる勇気 託し合って
Intersecting courage, entrusting it to each other!
Never Give Up! さあ夜明けへ
Never Give Up! Come on, towards the dawn!
怖さ 弱さは 涙は ちぎっては分け合い
Fear, weakness, and tears—tear them off and share them,
勝利を掴め！
And seize the victory!
握れば握るほど また開く意味を知り
The tighter you grip, the more you learn the meaning of opening your hand again.
相手の悲痛が伝わり 無刀の極みへ焦がれる
Feeling the opponent's anguish, longing for the ultimate state of swordlessness.
因縁の連鎖にこそ 撃鉄を起こせ…か
"Cock the hammer against the chain of fate..." is it?
鎮魂歌じゃなく 奏で合ったら？
What if we perform together instead of a requiem?
オレの知らない ぬくもりが
A warmth I never knew...
「誰かの想い出」の中
In "someone's memories,"
生きているのだと知ったなら？
if I learned that I was living?
完全否定以外にも 足掻く道があるんだと
That beyond total denial, there's a path to struggle through
だから絶対 この手と
So absolutely, with this hand...
不器用な この手は
These clumsy hands of mine...
差し伸べる 祈りを 忘れはしない
Will never forget the prayer they reach out with!
だから奮え！ 痛みを抱き
So stand up and fight! Embracing the pain,
わかり合える そう打ち込め！
we can understand each other, so fire away!
みんなで作った 歌の願いだ！
This is the wish of the song we all created!
重なる勇気 許す勇気 Never give up
Overlapping courage, forgiving courage, never give up!
さあ全霊の…
Come, with all our soul...
善も悪もごった煮の 世界を愛せ！
Love this world where good and evil are all mixed together!
世界を愛せ！
Love the world!
大好きな歌の中なら 声にしてもいいのかな…
If it's inside my favorite song, is it okay to voice it aloud?
想い出が強さになった 君ならば歌えるはず
Memories became my strength, you should be able to sing too
今日という 過去が生まれて
A past called "today" is born,
未来には どう居たいか 描くんだ
painting how we want to exist in the future!
心からの 「ありがとう」を 歌ってあげたいんだ
I want to sing a heartfelt "thank you" to you!
100度負けても 101度目に 勝てると笑う
Smiling that even if we lose 100 times, we can win on the 101st
この源とは？
What is the source of this power?
みんなで 繋いだ 歌のひびきだ！
It's the echo of the song we all connected together!
交わる勇気 託し合って Never give up
Courage to intersect, entrusting one another, never give up!
さあ夜明けへの…
Now, toward the dawn...
始まりを 吠え歌え X-BRAVERS
Roar and sing the beginning, X-BRAVERS!
勝利をつかめ！
Grasp victory!